



Muhammad Moiz Siddique

(+92) 3062890575 | muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com |

https://www.muhammadmoizsiddique.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddigue-74419b166/

Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991

Flat no. B-805, Al-minal tower, Block 3A, Gulistan e Johar, 75200, Karachi, Pakistan

About me:

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Associate Software Developer with over 3+ years of experience leading projects by acting as an architect, developer and programmer analyst.

WORK EXPERIENCE

07/06/2022 - CURRENT - Karachi, Pakistan

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - THE DESIGNRY

- I'm working as **team lead** on more than 2+ project, having a **team of 4 peoples**.
- I worked with modern javascript frameworks and libraries such as Angular, React JS, Node JS, React Native, etc.
- Integrated **third-party tools** and components into applications.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and **API-centric infrastructures**.
- · Organize a daily scrum meeting to identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- Manage & update the CI/CD pipeline, review and debug code and working with Kubernetes, Docker, AWS and AZURE.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements and manage **IIRA** tickets.
- Tested troubleshooting methods and documented resolutions for inclusion in knowledge base for support team
- Implement modern/best programming techniques and infrastructures such as SOLID principles, SaaS,
 Procedural Programming, Object-oriented Programming, Functional Programming, etc.

01/06/2019 - 31/05/2022 - Karachi, Pakistan

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER - ALGORACK INC.

- \circ Working on Full Stack Technologies such as $\textbf{Angular},\,\textbf{React Js},\,\textbf{Node JS}$ and others.
- Improved application designs with addition of new features and infrastructure.
- Integrated Build systems for example **Bable** and **Webpacks**.
- Handle API Integration and Wekhooks
- $\circ\,$ Optimised test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- Created successful test scripts to manage automated feature testing.
- Handle deployments on Cloud platforms such as AWS and Github actions for deployment pipelines.
- Integrate Payment gateways using third party tools such as Stripe API
- Worked with sql and noSql databases such as Mongodb, MySql, Sql server, postgress Sql.
- Handle client meetings and manage **JIRA** tickets.
- Completed various project few are from the scratch and I'm the lead developer having a small team to work on.

01/06/2018 – 31/10/2018 – Karachi, Pakistan

INTERNSHIP - KARACHI PORT TRUST (KPT)

- I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals.
- I learnt (Dot) Net programming language.
- I was exposed to the software infrastructure used in such a large sized professional company.
- Thoroughly understand how data centers are utilized in such large organizations works.
- This further helped me increase my **team-working creditability** working within a professional IT department and understanding the **workplace dynamic**.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

16/10/2017 – 18/06/2021 – Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, Karachi, Pakistan **BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE –** Mohammad Ali Jinnah University

PROJECTS

SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO - (https://www.socialchamp.io/)

Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Mongo db.

Responsibilities: **Design and develop** new modules, maintain and manage existing application including **bug fixes**, analyze requirement and **estimate ETAs**.

THINK EVOLVE SOLVE - (https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/)

Tech Stack: Angular, Node Js, Azure.

Responsibilities: I'm the **team lead** on this project having **2 members team** to Design, develop and manage frontend, backend and **data pipelines** and **cloud architectures** with **efficient processing** and management of large amounts of data, also **develop interfaces / APIs** for data exchange in Node Is.

Bright Development - (https://bright-development.com/);

Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db.

Responsibilities: **Team lead**, manage daily **workflow**, work on client proposed modules and make sure to provide high quality work, write **test for every new module**, manage and maintain **CI/CD pipeline**, **daily scrum** with team members, handle **client meeting**, manage **JIRA** and assigned work to team.

Black Lion App - (In progress)

Tech Stack: React JS, Node Js, Mongo db, Redis, AWS, All Social Media developer APIs, others.

Responsibilities: Worked from scratch on this project and i'm the Team lead, having a 4 person team to manage, esti mate ETAs, organize a daily scrum meeting to identify, prioritize and execute tasks, daily client meeting, understand client stories and assigned work to the team accordingly, manage and maintain CI/CD pipelines, using SaaS manage to communicate with cloud services, review and debug code, manage Github actions, update and maintain story board, review and merge pull request on Github.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

08/06/2022

JavaScript: Core And Advanced Techniques - Udemy: Online Courses

12/08/2020

Speed Programming (Code Jam) - Google

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND PLATFORMS

JAVASCRIPT / TYPESCRIPT / JAVA / PYTHON / C / C++ / C# / DOT (NET) / GO LANG / PHP / LARAVEL / HTML / CSS / DJANGO / FLASK / TENSERFLOW

WEB AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT

ANGULAR / REACT JS / NODE JS / STENCIL JS / NEST JS / REACT NATIVE / AZURE / AWS / GOOGLE CLOUD / OAUTH / CI-CD PIPELINES / DOCKER / KUBERNETES / AI / GIT / JIRA / BITBUCKET / HEROKU

DATABASE SKILLS

MONGO DB / MY SQL / SQL SERVER / POSTGRESS SQL / REDIS / ORACLE

LANGUAGES

Urdu (Native) / English (Fluent) / Turkish (Basics)